# 天气开始凉了
It’s getting cold these days
# 咱们得弄一冬天喝的
Let’s make something perfect for the winter season
# 叫花生奶酪
It’s called Peanut Milk Junket
# 今天就是一盘花生米 还有两袋奶
We only need some peanuts, two bags of milk
# 先把这花生米给它炸一下
First let’s fry the peanuts
# 花生米去皮有一个小窍门
There is a small trick in removing the peanut skin
# 开水烫两遍
Soak it twice in hot water
# 泡的时间不要太长
Not for too long
# 泡得了赶快捻 特别好捻
Quickly soak them in hot water then peal the skin off immediate
# 一泡长了
If you soak them for two long
# 花生米一涨再捻就不好捻了
The peanut will absorb too much water and swell, making it too difficult to peal its skin
# 凉油下锅慢慢浸炸
Peanuts in, while the oil is still cold and fry them slowly
# 花米不炸它不香 必须要炸一下
You must fry the peanuts to get the maximum aroma
# 在家里边不愿吃炸的也没问题
If you are cooking at home and you want to avoid frying
# 也可以烤一烤
You can also roast it
# 冒泡了你看啊 关小火
See the little bubbles? Now let’s lower the heat
# 开始大火因为油是凉的
We start with high heat to warm up the oil quickly
# 等冒泡了以后火要小一点
Once the bubbles come out, we need to lower the heat
# 攉拢的时候听听声音
Listen while you stir it
# 你看这声音有点发闷
It sounds a bit muffled
# 现在表面这些泡
These bubbles that are coming out
# 就是花生米当中的水分
They are moisture in the peanuts
# 平时炸花生米
When you fry peanuts
# 最不好炸的是带皮的花生米
It’s more difficult when the skins are still intact
# 你看不见颜色
Because you cannot see the color change
# 还有就是
Also
# 泡的时间稍微长一点的花生米
Those that have been soaked for too long
# 在炸的时候很容易扒锅
They will stick to the pan
# 如果泡时间长了
If you soak them for too long
# 我们可以放这儿先晾一晾
You can first leave them drying for a while
# 或者入烤箱弄八十度
Ow roast them in a 80 degree oven
# 烤它三分钟两分钟
For about 2-3 minutes
# 脱出去水分再开始炸
Remove the moisture and then start frying
# 炸出来以后
When fried properly
# 花生米的表面它不起泡 特别的酥脆
The peanuts will have smooth surface and be extremely crispy
# 听声啊 看这泡也少了
Listen to that, there are less bubbles now
# 温水洗
Wash them with warm water
# 表面漂起了油花 给它洗掉了
To get rid of the excess oil
# 开始粉碎
Now we can grind them
# 来点纯净水
Add pure water
# 一按
Here we go
# 这个渣子再搁点奶
We can pour some milk to these residues
# 熬成粗渣子有口感的
And cook them into a little bit of a rough texture
# 喝的时候有点像咱们那个棒子面粥
A bit like the corn flake porridge
# 好了 开火
OK bring the heat on
# 二伯 你看这浆都挂勺 很稠
Look how thick this is, Er Bai, it’s sticking to the spoon
# 两盒奶
Two bottles of milk
# 冰糖大爷咱搁进去了
Let me put the crystal sugar in
# 搁点冰糖或者是砂糖
Either crystal sugar or powdered sugar is fine
# 稠 叫酪
This junket is expected to be thick
# 稀的像这样的 就像茶
Thinner dishes like this are similar to tea, like Mee Teh
# 酪就要挂点杯子 稍微稠一点
It has to be a bit sticky, a bit thick
# 就是米汤芡
Like a thick porridge
# 早年我们国宴当中
Back in the days when we were preparing the State Banquet
# 有很多根据宴会（人数）的多与少
Depending on the number of participants
# 什么杏仁茶 花生奶酪
We would make Almond tea, or this peanut milk junket
# 这是多的
For a large group
# 小宴会上我们就拔丝苹果了 八宝饭
For a smaller group we would make toffee apple, or Ba Bao Rice
# 像这种几百人上千人的宴会
For large groups with hundreds of people
# 就得给这个了
We need this
# 花生奶酪杏仁茶
Dishes like this or the apricot kernel tea
# 小型宴会还有什么
For a small banquet
# 像夏天的杏仁豆腐
We also make apricot kernel jelly for the summer
# 淀粉拢点芡
We need some slurry in there
# 基本上米汤芡
A thin slurry
# 因为这叫酪 这酪好喝啊
This is junket. Very delicious!
# 可以加点东西
You can add other ingredients in here
# 加点西米 西米酪 西米花生酪
Like sago
# 还可以搁点椰米 搁水果也行
Or coconut, or fruits
# 这就好啦
That’s done
# 咱们把这浮沫篦出去
Let’s use the sieve to make it clean
# 有这浮沫它不好看 也不好吃
It will look better, and taste better
# 八成满就行了
Fill it up to 80%
# 现在已经好了 非常香
Smells so good
# 花生奶酪 二伯尝尝呗
Here we have it! Peanut Milk Junket. Have a taste, Er Bai!
# 都有奶皮子
The milk forms a skin on the surface
# 你说这营养价值
Must be very nutritious
# 和蛋白质 丰富不丰富
Rich in protein
# 先让二伯那酝着
Let Er Bai savor it
# 来 隋坡尝尝
Here, Sui Po, have a taste too.
# 二伯那体会呢 正在砸么滋味呢
Er Bai is enjoying it
# 师父炸这花生火候特别合适
This peanut is fried to perfection
# 出香味了 它没有糊味 很香
Aromatic, but not burnt
# 还有奶香味跟花生的香味
I also tasted the beautiful flavor of the milk and peanuts
# 融合到一起入口以后 还有挂口的感觉
All combined together in your mouth, and it is slightly sticky
# 香甜 口感特别好 细腻
Sweet, smooth
# 最关键是什么
More importantly
# 冬天养生的非常好的一种甜品
This is perfect for the winter season
# 对于我来说
For me
# 它不单单的是一碗酪的问题
This is more than a bowl of junket
# 大爷今天给我呈现的是满满的回忆
This is full of memories
# 我参加工作二十几岁的时候
When I started working at around 20 years old
# 我们曾经做这个酪
We used to make this dish
# 今天大爷再现
Seeing this again
# 不但是传承
It’s not only about inheriting
# 而且是我们对生活的一种回忆
But also a reflect of our lives
# 和我们对后人传承的一种态度
And our attitude towards inheritance.
# 这就是大爷的精神所在
That’s the spirit of Da Ye
# 谢谢二伯
Thank you Er Bai